Guide to the Stanford Energy Lectures
Stanford University Libraries.
Dept. of Special Collections & amp; University Archives.
Stanford energy lectures
1974-1984
Sc0212
Stanford University. Institute for Energy Studies.
30 Linear feet
Lectures, primarily by non-Stanford professors and energy professionals, on all aspects of energy studies, including fossil fuels, nuclear power, conservation, solar energy, energy industries, energy policy, and political considerations.
Dept. of Special Collections & amp; University Archives. Stanford University Libraries. 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: speccollref@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1985.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Institute for Energy Studies, organized in 1973, was designed to stimulate, facilitate, and promote the development of research and academic programs in energy within existing schools and departments.
TIhe Stanford energy lectures, dating from 1974 to 1984, were prilnarily by non-Stanford professors and energy industry professionals, which include audience interaction, are in two fonnats: 1/2 inch EIAJ-format videotape and 3/4 inch video cassette.
In addition to the following item list, there is a card file index to these tapes.
Description of the Collection
Lectures, primarily by non-Stanford professors and energy professionals, on all aspects of energy studies, including fossil fuels, nuclear power, conservation, solar energy, energy industries, energy policy, and political considerations. The tapes, which include audience interaction, are in two fonnats: 1/2 inch EIAJ-format videotape (indicated on the list by vr) and 3/4 inch videocassette (indicated by VC).
Access Terms
Stanford University. Institute for Energy Studies.; Energy conservation.; Energy development.; Energy industries.; Energy policy.; Fossil fuels.; Nuclear energy.; Power resources.; Solar energy.; Videorecordings.
Collection Contents
- Stanford Energy Lectures
  - Keith Doig, Vice President, Shell Oil Company, THE U.S. OIL SUPPLY IN THE LIGHT OF THE INTERNATIONAL SITUATION, 1974 Feb 11; 1; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Milton F. Searl, Manager, Energy Supply Studies Program, Electric Power Research Institute, DOMESTIC ENERGY FUTURES --A DIFFERENT VIEW., 1974 Feb 22; 4; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Chauncey Starr, President, EPRI, and Consulting Professor, Stanford University, GENERAL PHILOSOPHY OF RISK-BENEFIT ANALYSIS., 1974 Sep 30; 5; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Lester Lave, Chairman, Department of Economics, Graduate School of Industrial Administration, Carnegie-Mellon University, HEALTH EFFECTS OF ELECTRICITY GENERATION FROM COAL, OIL AND NUCLEAR FUEL, 1974 Oct 14; 7; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Kenneth Arrow, Depar tment of Economics, Harvard University, THE RATE OF DISCOUNT FOR LONG-TERM PUBLIC INVESTMENT, 1974 Oct 28; 9; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Wolf Hafele, International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis, Vienna, BENEFIT - RISK TRADEOFFS IN NUCLEAR POWER GENERATION., 1974 Nov 14; 10; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. E. J. Gornowski, Executive Vice Presiden t, Exxon Research and Engineering Company, OPTIONS FOR THE CONVERSION OF FOSSIL FUELS, 1974 Nov 11; 11; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Alan S. Manne, Professor of Political Economy, Kennedy School, Harvard University, U.S. STRATEGY FOR A TRANSITION FROM FOSSIL TO NUCLEAR FUELS., 1974 Nov 18; 12; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Gerald J. Lieberman, Professor of Operations Research and Statistics, Stanford University, FAULT-TREE ANALYSIS AS AN EXAMPLE OF RISK METHODOLOGY., 1974 Nov 25; 13; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Richard J. Gonzalez, Visiting Professor of Energy Economics, Stanford University, ENERGY AND HUMAN WELFARE., 1974 Nov 13; 15; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - M. King Hubbert, Research Geologist, U.S. Geological Survey, MAN'S CONQUEST OF ENERGY: ITS ECOLOGICAL AND HUMAN CONSEQUENCES., 1973 Oct 8; 17; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Paul Swatek, Massachusetts Audubon Society, ENERGY CONSERVATION IN CONSUMER PRODUCTS., 1975 Feb 3; 21; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - John Sawhill, Ford Foundation, CONSERVATION AND NATIONAL POLICY, 1975 Feb 24; 22; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Chauncey Starr, President, EPRI, ENERGY AND SOCIETY., 1975 Jan 7; 24; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Thomas Connolly, Associate Chairman, Dept. of Mechanical Engineering, Stanford University, CAN WE LIVE WITH PLUTONIUM?, 1973 Apr 14; 25; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Mr. Dwain Spencer, Program Manager, Solar and Geothermal Energy, EPRI, SOLAR ENERGY--MYTH OR REALITY?, 1975 Apr 28; 26; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - THE PLUTONIUM CONNECTION. From "Nova," KQED broadcast. Not for rent., 1975 Mar 28; 26A; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Hewlett-Packard, Automatic Measurement Division, AMD SOLAR ENERGY HEATING PROJECT, Palo Alto, 1975, 31A; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. George Lof, Vice President and Technical Director, Solaron Corporation, CAPTURING AND USING SOLAR RADIATION, 1975 Oct 13; 33; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Mr. Oystein Noreng, Planning Department, Royal Ministry of Finance, Norway, NORWEGIAN OIL INDUSTRY--A CHALLENGE TO PLANNING AND INTEGRATION., 1975 Oct 20; 34; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dan Shoemaker, ABC Evening News, interviewing Professor Channing Robertson, Stanford University, on EUCALYPTUS TREES AS AN ENERGY SOURCE., 1975 Oct 25; 34A; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. George Hill, Director, Fossil Fuel Department, EPRI, WORLD TECHNOLOGICAL DEVELOPMENTS IN FOSSIL FUELS., 1975 Oct 27; 35; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Dixy Lee Ray, Former Chairman of Atomic Energy Commission, OVERVIEW OF THE U.S. POSITION IN WORLD ENERGY TECHNOLOGY AND TRADE., 1975 Nov 3; 36; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Pierre Zaleski, Director, Technicatome, THE FRENCH BREEDER REACTOR PROGRAM--ITS OBJECTIVES AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS., 1975 Nov 17; 38; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Professor Henr y J. Ramey, Department of Petroleum Engineering, Stanford University, SECONDARY AND TERTIARY RECOVERY OF PETROLEUM., 1975 Nov 24; 39; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Henry Linden, President, Institute of Gas Technology, TECHNICAL AND ECONOMIC ISSUES IN ENERGY POLICY., 1975 Dec 1; 40; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Chauncey Starr, President, EPRI, A STRATEGY OF NATIONAL ENERGY PRODUCTION., 1976 Jan 19; 43; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Professor Joseph E. Stiglitz, Department of Economics, Stanford University, SOME ASPECTS OF THE ECONOMICS OF NATURAL RESOURCE ALLOCATION., 1976 Jan 26; 44; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Alan S. Marine, Professor of Political Economy, Kennedy School, Harvard University, INTERDEPENDENCE BETWEEN ENERGY SUPPLY AND ECONOMY-WIDE GROWTH., 1976 Mar 8; 49; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Channing Robertson, Associate Professor, Chemical Engineering Department, Stanford University, BEYOND PETROLEUM: EDUCATIONAL CHALLENGE., 1976 May 5; 50; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. John Holdren, Associate Professor of Energy and Resources, University of California, Berkeley, ruSION POWER AND THE ENVIRONMENT --AS SAFE AS ADVERTISED?, 1976 Apr 12; 51; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Peter Auer, Professor of Aerospace Engineering, Cornell University, NATIONAL ENERGY STRATEGIES., 1976 Apr 19; 52; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Richard Balzhiser, Director, Fossil Fuels and Advanced Systems Division, EPRI, ENERGY SUPPLY CHALLENGES, 1976 Apr 26; 53; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Mr. Richard Maullin, Chairman, California State Energy Resources Conservation and Development Commission, ENERGY ISSUES WITHIN CALIFORNIA., 1976 May 3; 54; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Cyril Comar, Director, Environmental Assessment Department, Energy Systems, Environment and Conservation Division, EPRI, PUBLIC HEALTH ASPECTS OF ENERGY TECHNOLOGY., 1976 May 10; 55; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Professor Laura Nader, Department of Anthropology, University of California, Berkeley, HUMAN FACTORS IN THE ENERGY QUESTION., 1976 Oct 25; 60; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Mr. Leland Gardner, Manager, Rate Department, PG& E, UTILITY RATE REFORM-- THE LIFE-LINE CONCEPT., 1976 Nov 15; 63; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Mr. Robert Uhler, Executive Director, Electric Rate Design Study, EPRI, UTILITY RATE REFORM., 1976 Nov 22; 64; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Representative Mike McCormack, Sub-Committee on Energy Research, Development and Demonstration, Committee on Science and Technology, THE FUTURE OF U.S. ENERGY POLICY., 1976 Nov 29; 65; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Alan Pasternak, Commissioner, California Energy Resources Conservation and Development Commission, GOALS FOR CALIFORNIA ENERGY POLICY., 1977 Jan 17; 67; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Professor Henry Rowen, Stanford Graduate School of Business, NUCLEAR PROLIFERATION AND SPENT FUEL REPROCESSING., 1977 Feb 28; 68; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Dorothy Nelkin, Associate Professor, Program on Science, Technology and Society, Department of City and Regional Planning, Cornell University, NUCLEAR POWER AND THE PUBLIC- - SOME EUROPEAN EXPERIMENTS IN PARTICIPATION., 1977 Apr 4; 70; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Philip J. Farley, Visiting Scholar, Arms Control and Disarmament Program, Stanford University, NUCLEAR POWER ISSUES AND CHOICES., 1977 May 2; 71; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Peter Gillingham and Patrick Long, Intermediate Technology of Menlo Park, A REPORT ON THE STATUS OF APPROPRIATE TECHNOLOGY AROUND THE UNITED STATES., 1977 May 9; 72; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Professor David A. Pilati, Center for Advanced Computation, University of Illinois at Urbana, RESIDENTIAL/COMMERCIAL ENERGY USE THROUGH THE YEAR 2010., 1977 May 16; 73; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Professor A. J. Lichtenberg, Department of Electrical Engineering, University of California, Berkeley, EFFICIENT ENERGY USE AND WELL-BEING--THE SWEDISH EXAMPLE., 1977 May 23; 74; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Chauncey Starr, President, EPRI, PROSPECTS FOR ADVANCED ELECTRICITY SOURCES., 1977 Oct 10; 76; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Paul F. Rappaport, Director, Solar Energy Research Institute, Golden, Colorado, SERI--ITS HOPES AND ASPIRATIONS., 1977 Oct 17; 77; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Oystein Noreng, Professor, Oslo Institute of Business Administration, THE WORLD OIL MARKET UNTIL 1990--PRICE DEVELOPMENT AND THE INTERACTION BETWEEN OECD COUNTRIES AND OPEC COUNTRIES., 1977 Nov 7; 78; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Mr. Ben C. Ball, Jr., Vice President, Gulf Oil Corporation, THE EFFECTIVENESS OF ENERGY POLICY AND PLANNING TOOLS IN THE PUBLIC AND PRIVATE SECTORS., 1977 Nov 21; 79; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Robert C. Seamans, Jr., Henry Luce Professor, M. I.T. and former Administrator, ERDA, ENERGY DEVELOPMENT AND PUBLIC POLICY., 1977 Nov 28; 80; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Professor Stanford S. Penner, Director, Energy Center, University of California, San Diego, THE ROLE OF SMALL-SCALE ENERGY TECHNOLOGIES IN THE NATIONAL ENERGY PLAN., 1978 Feb 6; 82; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Professor George Pickering, Associate Professor of Social Ethics, University of Detroit, ISSUES OF CENTRALIZATION & DECENTRALIZATION IN ENERGY POLICY, 1978 Mar 6; 83; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Professor Denton E. Morrison, Professor of Sociology, Michigan State University, SOCIAL EQUITY PROBLEMS IN ENERGY POLICY, 1978 Mar 13; 84; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Amory B. Lovins, Friends of the Earth, Regents Lecturer, University of California, Berkeley, SOFT ENERGY PATHS., 1978 Apr 17; 85; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Cyril L. Comar, Director, Environmental Assessment, EPRI, HEALTH RISKS FROM COAL AND NUCLEAR POWER: ESTIMATIONS, PERCEPTIONS AND ACCEPTANCE., 1978 May 1; 86; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Joseph E. Coates, Assistant to the Director, Office of Technology Assessment, ENERGY DEMAND MANAGEMENT--THE REVOLUTIONARY ROLE FOR GOVERNMENT., 1978 May 8; 87; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Edwin L. Zebroski, Director, Nuclear Systems and Materials, EPRI, WORLD ENERGY OPTIONS AND NUCLEAR PROLIFERATION., 1978 May 15; 88; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - "William M. Kays, Dean of School of Engineering; William C. Reynolds, Chairman, Department of Mechanical Engineering; and Stephen J. Kline, Professor of Mechanical Engineering; INTRODUCTION TO APPLIED THERMODYNAMICS AND HEAT TRANSFER- - A GLANCE FORWARD AND BACK. A PROGRAM IN HONOR OF PROFESSOR A. LOUIS LONDON. London Day", 1978 May 12; 88a; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Welko E. Gasich, Group Executive, Aircraft Group, Northrop Corporation, INTEGRATION OF PROPULSION, PAYLOAD, AND VEHICLE-TRADE-OFFS ON SYSTEM INTEGRATION FOR MODERN AIRCRAFT. London Day, 1978 May 12; 88b; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - John W. Mitchell, Professor of Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin, DESIGN CONSIDERATIONS FOR RESIDENTIAL SOLAR-HEAT PUMP SYSTEMS. London Day, 1978 May 12; 88c; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Long Sun Tong, Assistant Director, Reactor Safety Research Division, Nuclear Regulatory Commission, HEAT TRANSFER AND WATER REACTOR SAFETY. London Day, 1978 May 12; 88d; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Robert F. Sawyer, Professor of Mechanical Engineering, University of- California, Berkeley, CALIFORNIA'S LEADERSHIP- ROLE IN AIR POLLUTION- CONTROL. London Day, 1978 May 12; 88e; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr John L. Mason, Vice President, Engineering, Garrett Corporation, VEHICULAR GAS TURBINES--PURE AND HYBRID., 1978 May 12; 88f; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Rene Condoni, Project ZENCAP, Zurich, FUTURE ENERGY NEEDS AND CAPITAL CAPACITY IN GLOBAL PERSPECTIVE., 1978 Oct 26; 90; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Bob Uhler, Director, Department of Energy Analysis, EPRI, ELECTRICITY PRICING ALTERNATIVES., 1978 Nov 2; 91; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - David Wood, Associate Director, MIT Energy Laboratory, MODEL ASSESSMENT IN THE POLICY RESEARCH PROCESS., 1978 Nov 9; 92; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - David Sternlight, Chief Economist, Atlantic Richfield Company, INFLUENCING ENERGY POLICY WITH ANALYSIS., 1978 Nov 16; 93; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Tom Keelin, Decision Focus, Inc., ELECTRIC POWER SYSTEM PLANNING UNDER UNCERTAINTY: COSTS AND BENEFITS OF OVER/UNDER DECISIONS., 1978 Nov 30; 94; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Alan Manne, Department of Operations Research, Stanford University, ENERGY TRANSITION: STRATEGIES FOR THE INDUSTRIALIZED NATIONS., 1978 Dec 7; 95; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Jay Kopelman, Manager, Special Studies, EPRI, A GLOBAL ENERGY PERSPECTIVE., 1979 Feb 15; 96; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Cal KilgQre, Chief, Division of International Energy Analysis, Energy Information Administration, Department of Energy, THE INTERNATIONAL FORECASTS IN THE EIA'S ANNUAL ADMINISTRATORS' REPORT., 1979 Feb 22; 97; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. C. Roger Glassey, Assistant Administrator for Planning and Analysis, Energy Information Administration, Department of Energy, SCENARIO DESIGN FOR THE 1978 ELA ADMINISTRATORS' ANNUAL REPORT., 1979 Feb 8; 98; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Andrew Van Horn, Head, Engineering Systems Division, Teknekron, Inc., ANALYSIS SUPPORTING THE EPA'S INTERPRETATION OF AMENDMENTS TO THE CLEAN AIR ACT., 1979 Apr 5; 99; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Dermot Gately. Department of Economics, New York University, MODELING OPEC BEHA VIOR., 1979 May 3; 100; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Nathan Buras, Department of Operations Research, Stanford University, WATER CONSTRAINTS IN ENERGY MODELS., 1979 May 10; 101; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Michael Kennedy, Rand Corporation, RAND RESEARCH ON THE WORLD OIL MARKET., 1979 May 31; 102; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Dr. Leonard Hamilton, Head, Biomedical Division, Brookhaven National Laboratory, HEALTH EFFECTS OF FOSSIL FUEL COMBUSTION., 1979 Jul 26; 103; 1 videotape(s) (EIAJ-1)
  - Richard Nehring, Pilind Corporation, WORLD OIL AND GAS RESOURCES., 1979 Nov 8; 104; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Thomas Connolly, Professor, Mechanical Engineering Department, Stanford University, THE NUCLEAR CONTROVERSY. Lecture given to ME180 class., 1979 Nov 28; 104a; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Dr. Mans Lonnroth, Senior Scientist, Institute for Future Studies, Beijr Institute, Stockholm, Sweden, LONG- TERM ENERGY FUTURES FOR SWEDEN: NUCLEAR COMMITMENTS AND SOLAR OPTIONS., 1980 Jan 10; 105; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Dr. John P. Weyent, Deputy Director, Energy Modeling Forum, DECREASING OUR DEPENDENCE ON PERSIAN GULF OIL: NEED AND OPPORTUNITIES., 1980 Jan 17; 106; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - James L. Plummer, Director, Energy Analysis Department, EPRI, AN ECONOMIST'S PERSPECTIVE ON SYNTHETIC FUELS., 1980 Feb 4; 107; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Elmer L. Dougherty, Professor of Petroleum Engineering, USC, and Jeffery B. Nugent, Professor of Economics, USC, AN OVERVIEW OF THE OPEC WORLD ENERGY MODEL., 1980 Feb 7; 108; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Robert V. Steele, Senior Analyst, SRI International, ENVIRONMENTAL CONSIDERATIONS IN SYNTHETIC FUEL PLANT SITING., 1980 Feb 11; 109; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Lucian Pugliaresi, Director, Office of Oil Policy, U.S. Department of Energy, ANALYSIS OF ACQUISITION AND DRAW DOWN POLICIES FOR THE STRATEGIC PETROLEUM RESERVE (SPR), 1980 Feb 14; 110; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Chauncey Starr, Vice Chairman, EPRI, SURVEY OF ENERGY ALTERNATIVES FOR THE UNITED STATES., 1980 Feb 21; 111; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - John Boatwright, Coordinator of Economics, Exxon USA, THE U.S. ENERGY OUTLOOK TO THE YEAR 2000., 1980 Feb 25; 112; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - James L. Sweeney, Director, Energy Modeling Forum, U.S. OIL AND GAS SUPPLY., 1980 Feb 28; 113; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Mason Willrich, PG& E, CALIFORNIA'S COAL OPTION., 1980 Mar 6; 114; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Richard E. Balzhiser, Vice President, Research and Development, EPRI, SYNTHETIC FUELS--PUTTING OUR OPTIONS IN PERSPECTIVE., 1980 Apr 14; 115; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - "Peter M. Schwolsky, Washington Representative/Legal Advisor, EPRI, SYNTHETIC FUELS--THE WASHINGTON SCENE. ", 1980 Apr 21; 116; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Larry Jacobson, Federal Reserve Board, International Finance Division, THE CHANGING STRUCTURE OF THE WORLD OIL MARKET, 1980 Apr 24; 117; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Carleton B. Scott, Director, Environmental Sciences Department, Union Oil of California, THE ENVIRONMENTAL PROBLEMS OF SITING A COMMERICAL OIL SHALE PLANT, 1980 Apr 28; 118; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Richard Pefley, Professor of Mechanical Engineering, University of Santa Clara, USE OF ALCOHOL AS ALTERNATIVE FUEL., 1980 May 12; 119; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - "Lincoln E. Moses, Professor of Statistics, Stanford University, A STATISTICiAN'S ADVENTURES IN THE DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY", 1980 Oct 13; 121; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Theodore H. Moran, Professor and Director, Program in International Business Diplomacy, School of Foreign Service, Georgetown University. MODELING OPEC BEHAVIOR., 1980 Oct 20; 122; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Alan Manne, Professor of Operations Research, Stanford University. OIL STOCKPILE POLICIES TO REDUCE ECONOMIC VULNERABILITY., 1980 Oct 27; 123; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Dr. John McCarthy, Professor of Computer Science, Stanford University. EXTREME ENERGY CONSER VATION MEASURES IN AN OIL CUT-OFF EMERGENCY., 1980 Nov 3; 124; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Donald S. Duncan, Manager, Nuclear Fuel Cycle Safety, Bechtel National, Inc. STATUS OF THE U.S. PROGRAM ON HIGH-LEVEL NUCLEAR HASTE DISPOSAL., 1980 Nov 10; 125; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Charles K.Ebinger, Director of the Program on Energy & National Security Center for Strategic & International.Studies, Georgetown University.TREMORS IN WORLD OIL: THE CONSEQUENCES FOR U. S. DOMESTIC AND INTERNATIONAL ENERGY POLICY., 1980 Nov 17; 126; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - J. Michael Gallagher, Technical Director, World Coal Study; Assistant to Manager, Research & Engineering, Bechtel National, Inc. COAL: STRATEGIC NECESSITY, ECONOMIC OPPORTUNITY., 1980 Nov 24; 127; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Gunnar T. Nilsson, Marketing Director, Swedyards International, Inc. BARGE-MOUNTED PETROCHEMICAL PLANTS FOR CONVERSION OF NATURAL GAS TOMETHANOL, 1980 Dec 1; 128; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Thomas J. Connolly, Prof. Mechanical Engineering, Stanford University. WINDS OF CHANGE: ZEPHYRS OR TORNADOES?, 1981 Jan 12; 129; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Joseph R. Rensch, President, Pacific Lighting Corp. THE EMERGING ROLE OF GAS: OPPORTUNIES AND PROBLEMS., 1981 Jan 19; 130; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - John E. Bryson, President, California Public Utilities Commission. ENERGY UTILITIES: THE NEXT TEN YEARS., 1981 Jan 26; 131; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - H. Fred Christie, Executive Vice President, Chief Financial Officer, Southern California Edison Co. FINANCIAL PLANNING: SOME STRATEGIES FOR THE ELECTRIC UTILITIES IN THE 80's., 1981 Feb 2; 132; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Aviel Verbruggen, Antwerp University, Belgium. FEASIBILITY CRITERIA FOR DISTRICT HEATING., 1981 Feb 9; 133; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Martin B. Zimmerman, National Fellow, Hoover Institution, Asst. Prof. of Management, MIT. WHATEVER HAPPENED TO NUCLEAR POWER?, 1981 Feb 23; 134; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Mason Willrich, Vice President - Corporate Planning, Pacific Gas & Electric Company. FINANCING ENERGY SERVICES., 1981 Mar 2; 135; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Benjamin Schlesinger, Vice President, Policy Evaluation and Analysis, American Gas Association. U.S. NATURAL GAS ENERGY SUPPLY AND DEMAND OUTLOOK., 1981 Apr 13; 137; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Harry C. Kent, Director, Potential Gas Agency, Mineral Resources Institute, Colorado School of Mines. THE OUTLOOK FOR REMAINING U.S. CONVENTIONAL NATURAL GAS RESOURCES., 1981 Apr 20; 138; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - John C. Sharer, Assistant Director, Unconventional Natural Gas Research Institute. U.S. SUPPLY POTENTIAL OF UNCONVENTIONAL NATURAL GAS., 1981 Apr 27; 139; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - "Sherman H. Clark and Klaus P. Rose, Sherman H. Clark Associates. A COMPARISON OF U. S. NATURAL GAS PRODUCTION FORECASTS.", 1981 May 4; 140; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Henry Rowen, Professor of Public Management, Graduate School of Business, Stanford University. MACROVIEW OF WORLD POTENTIAL FOR NATURAL GAS IN THE MEDIUM AND LONG TERM., 1981 May 11; 141; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - James K. A. Harral, Manager Gas Resources, Pacific Gas and Electric Company. PG& E's ASSESSMENT OF FUTURE GAS REQUIREMENTS AND SUPPLY., 1981 May 18; 142; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Thomas Connolly, Professor of Mechanical Engineering, Stanford University. EIGHT YEARS OF ENERGY CRISIS., 1981 Oct 5; 143; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Walter Esselman, Director of Strategic Planning, Electric Power Research Institute. THE NEED FOR NEW BASE-LOAD ELECTRIC CAPACITY., 1981 Oct 12; 144; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - James Sweeney, Prof. Engineering-Economic Systems and Director, Energy Modeling Forum, Stanford University. WORLD OIL - THE RESULTS OF THE EMF STUDY., 10/919/81; 145; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Ibrihim Kavrakoglu, Visiting Professor of Industrial Engineering, Bogazici University, Turkey. ELECTRICITY SUPPLY POLICIES IN DEVELOPING COUNTRIES., 1981 Nov 2; 146; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - David Teece, Associate Professor, Stanford Graduate School of Business. OPEC BEHAVIOR AND THE LONG-RUN PRICE OF OIL., 1981 Nov 9; 147; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Lee Schipper, Staff Scientist, Lawrence Berkeley Laboratory. MEASURING ENERGY USE AND CONSERVATION IN THE RESIDENTIAL SECTOR OF SOME MAJOR OECD COUNTRIES., 1981 Nov 16; 148; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Steven G. Boxer and Nathan Lewis, Professors, Chemistry Department, Stanford University. ARTIFICIAL PHOTOSYNTHESIS., 1981 Nov 23; 149; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)